WHAM! is a documentary, music film directed by Chris Smith.
Through archival interviews and footage, George Michael and
Andrew Ridgeley relive the arc of their Wham!
career, from 70s best buds to 80s pop icons.
Self, played by Andrew Ridgeley.
Self (archive footage), played by George Michael.
Self (archive footage), played by Elton John.
Self (archive footage), played by David Bowie.
Self (archive footage), played by Mick Jagger.
Self (archive footage), played by Sting.
is a 2023 British documentary film about the English pop duo Wham!
consisting of George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley.
The film marks the 40th anniversary of their 1983 debut album Fantastic.
Directed by Chris Smith it relies primarily on rare archive footage and audio interviews by the duo, including television appearances, concert footage,
private home video, behind-the-scenes outtakes, and family comments all linked together using scrapbooks created by Ridgeley's mother.
The film was co-produced by Ventureland / Passion Pictures, Nemperor Production, and
Library Films with Altitude Film and Netflix serving as distributors.
had its world premiere at the Sheffield DocFest on 17–18 June 2023 and given a
limited theatrical release in the United Kingdom on 27 June.
It was reviewed as a cleverly stitched together film, using audio
posthumously of Michael and new audio from Ridgeley.
It was released worldwide to stream on 5 July 2023 on Netflix and
received generally positive reviews from critics.
The film was nominated for a BAFTA Award for Best Documentary.
The film explores themes of friendship, pop culture,
archive footage, nostalgic, 1980s.
The tone is emotional.